[
    {
        "question": "Among the following option identify the one which is not a type of learning",
        "answer": "Answer - A) Semi unsupervised learning is incorrect.",
        "options": [
            "Semi unsupervised learning",
            "Supervised learning",
            "Reinforcement learning",
            "Unsupervised learning"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the kind of learning algorithm for  “facial identities for facial expressions”.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) For facial identities and facial expression, “recognition patterns” is used.",
        "options": [
            "Prediction",
            "Recognition patterns",
            "Recognizing anomalies",
            "Generating patterns"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the model which is trained with data in only a single batch.",
        "answer": "Answer - C) The model is trained with data in only a single batch. is known as batch learning or offline learning.",
        "options": [
            "Offline learning",
            "Batch learning",
            "Both A and B",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the application of machine learning methods to a large database called?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Application of machine learning methods to large databases is known as data mining.",
        "options": [
            "Big data computing",
            "Internet of things",
            "Data mining",
            "Artificial intelligence"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the type of learning in which labeled training data is used.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Supervised learning uses labeled training data.",
        "options": [
            "Semi unsupervised learning",
            "Supervised learning",
            "Reinforcement learning",
            "Unsupervised learning"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Among the following identify the one in which dimensionality reduction reduces.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) Dimensionality reduction reduces collinearity.",
        "options": [
            "Performance",
            "Entropy",
            "Stochastics",
            "Collinearity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following machine learning algorithm is based upon the idea of bagging?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Random forest is based on the idea of bagging.",
        "options": [
            "Decision tree",
            "Random-forest",
            "Classification",
            "Regression"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose a disadvantage of decision trees among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Decision trees are prone to overfitting.",
        "options": [
            "Decision trees are robust to outliers",
            "Factor analysis",
            "Decision trees are prone to overfit",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term known as on which the machine learning algorithms build a model based on sample data?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) The term is known as training data.",
        "options": [
            "Data training",
            "Training data",
            "Transfer data",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Machine learning is a subset of which of the following.",
        "answer": "Answer - A) Machine learning is a subset of artificial intelligence.",
        "options": [
            "Artificial intelligence",
            "Deep learning",
            "Data learning",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following machine learning techniques helps in detecting the outliers in data?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) The machine learning algorithm which helps in detecting the outliers is known as anomaly detection.",
        "options": [
            "Classification",
            "Clustering",
            "Anomaly detection",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The father of machine learning is _____________",
        "answer": "Answer - A) The father of machine learning is Geoffrey Everest Hinton.",
        "options": [
            "Geoffrey Everest Hinton",
            "Geoffrey Hill",
            "Geoffrey Chaucer",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The most significant phase in genetic algorithm is _________",
        "answer": "Answer - D) Crossover is the most significant figure in genetic algorithm",
        "options": [
            "Mutation",
            "Selection",
            "Fitness function",
            "Crossover"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are common classes of problems in machine learning?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) All of the above are common classes of problems in machine learning.",
        "options": [
            "Regression",
            "Classification",
            "Clustering",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following options identify the one which is false regarding regression.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) Option d is incorrect among the following.",
        "options": [
            "It is used for the prediction",
            "It is used for  interpretation",
            "It relates inputs to outputs",
            "It discovers casual relationships"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the successful applications of ML.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) All of the above are applications of ML.",
        "options": [
            "Learning to classify new astronomical structures",
            "Learning to recognize spoken words",
            "Learning to drive an autonomous vehicle",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the incorrect numerical functions in the various function representation of machine learning.",
        "answer": "Answer - A) Case-based is the correct answer",
        "options": [
            "Case-based",
            "Support vector machines",
            "Linear regression",
            "Neural network"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "FIND-S algorithm ignores?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) FIND-S algorithm ignores negative.",
        "options": [
            "Positive",
            "Negative",
            "Both",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the correct definition of neuro software.",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Neuro software is a powerful and easy neural network.",
        "options": [
            "It is software used by neurosurgeons",
            "It is software  used to analyze neurons",
            "It is a powerful and easy neural network",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Choose the general limitations of the backpropagation rule among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) All of the above general limitations of the backpropagation rule.",
        "options": [
            "Slow convergence",
            "Scaling",
            "Local minima problem",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Analysis of ML algorithm needs",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Analysis of ML algorithms needs both statistical learning theory and computational learning theory.",
        "options": [
            "Statistical learning theory",
            "Computational learning theory",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the most widely used mattress and tools to assess the classification models.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) All of the above are correct.",
        "options": [
            "The area under the ROC curve",
            "Confusion matrix",
            "Cost-sensitive accuracy",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Full form of PAC is _____________",
        "answer": "Answer - B) PAC stands for Probably Approximate Correct.",
        "options": [
            "Probably Approx Cost",
            "Probably Approximate Correct",
            "Probability Approx Communication",
            "Probably Approximate Computation"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Choose the options below of which the area CLT is comprised of.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) The area CLT is comprised of all of the above.",
        "options": [
            "Mistake bound",
            "Sample complexity",
            "Computational complexity",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the instance-based learner.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Lazy learner is an instance-based learner.",
        "options": [
            "Eager learner",
            "Lazy learner",
            "Both A and B are correct",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the difficulties with the k-nearest neighbor algorithm.",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Both A and B are correct.",
        "options": [
            "Curse of dimensionality",
            "Calculate the distance of the test case from all training cases",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The total types of the layer in radial basis function neural networks is ______",
        "answer": "Answer - C) There is a total of 3 types of layered in radial basis function neural networks.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an application of CBR?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Design is an application of CBR.",
        "options": [
            "Diagnosis",
            "Design",
            "Planning",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct advantages of CBR.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) All of the above advantages of CBR.",
        "options": [
            "Fast to train",
            "A local approx is found for each test case",
            "Knowledge is in a form understandable by human",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Machine learning as various Search and Optimisation algorithms. Identify among the following which is not evolutionary computation.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) Perceptron is not evolutionary computing.",
        "options": [
            "Genetic algorithm",
            "Genetic programming",
            "Neuroevolution",
            "Perceptron"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not machine learning disciplines?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) Neuro statistics is not a message landing discipline",
        "options": [
            "Information theory",
            "Optimisation + control",
            "Physics",
            "Neuro statistics"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does K stand for in K mean algorithm?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) K stands for a number of iterations in the K mean algorithm.",
        "options": [
            "Number of clusters",
            "Number of data",
            "Number of attributes",
            "Number of iterations"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Identify the clustering method which takes care of variance in data",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Gaussian mixture model takes care of variance in data",
        "options": [
            "Decision tree",
            "Gaussian mixture model",
            "K means",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a supervised learning",
        "answer": "Answer - A) PCA Is not supervised learning.",
        "options": [
            "PCA",
            "Naive Bayesian",
            "Linear regression",
            "Decision tree"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is unsupervised learning?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Unsupervised learning has neither feature nor number of groups known.",
        "options": [
            "Number of groups may be known",
            "Features of group explicitly stated",
            "Neither feature nor number of groups is known",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a machine learning algorithm?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) SVG Is not a machine learning algorithm.",
        "options": [
            "SVM",
            "SVG",
            "Random forest",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is true about Machine Learning?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) All of the above is true about machine learning.",
        "options": [
            "The main focus of ML is to allow computer systems to learn from experience without being explicitly programmed or human intervention.",
            "ML is a type of artificial intelligence that extracts patterns out of raw data by using an algorithm or method.",
            "Machine Learning (ML) is the field of computer science.",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not machine learning?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Rule-based inference is not  machine learning",
        "options": [
            "Artificial intelligence",
            "Rule-based inference",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the method which is used for trainControl resampling.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) repeatedcv is used for trainControl resampling.",
        "options": [
            "svm",
            "repeatedcv",
            "Bag32",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following option identify the one which is used to create the most common graph types.",
        "answer": "Answer - C) qplot is used to create the most common graph types",
        "options": [
            "plot",
            "quickplot",
            "qplot",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    }
]